Welcome to the Dangerous Goods Learning Series.
Did you know many dangerous goods can be sold on Amazon?
This is why, as a seller, you are required to provide accurate information about your
products.
In this video, we will share some examples of common products that you may not know are
dangerous goods.
Many of these products can be found around your home, let's go inside and take a look
around.
We will start in everyone's favorite room, the kitchen.
The kitchen contains aerosols such as glass cleaner and cooking sprays.
These items are categorized and regulated as dangerous goods because they contain compressed
gas and can sometimes be flammable.
Another product commonly found in kitchens are flavoring extracts.
That's right, even flavoring extracts such as vanilla used in baking can be flammable.
Now, let's walk into the bathroom to look at some health and beauty products.
Perfume, nail polish, deodorant sprays and even mouthwash containing alcohol are all
examples of products that can be flammable.
Also your digital thermometers and the wireless speaker in your shower contain lithium batteries
which make them regulated products.
And last but not least, hair dyes can be categorized and regulated as dangerous goods.
Next, let's look at wireless and electronic items in the office.
Lithium batteries in phones and laptops are categorized and regulated as dangerous goods.
Lithium batteries are regulated because they can be dangerous when they are damaged, crushed
or short circuited.
Other office items that can be regulated as dangerous goods are correction
fluid, air dusters, marker pens, and some high strength glues because they can be flammable.
Now to where we store everything else, the garage.
Power tools such as cordless drills use lithium batteries and are regulated.
Tire cleaners and degreasers keep wheels looking clean but are regulated as dangerous goods
due to their flammability.
Camping and sporting equipment are designed for fun but can be regulated as dangerous goods.
Typical examples include butane canisters and battery operated headlamps.
Let's go outside to see what dangerous goods we can find here.
First, let's take a look at the pool.
Did you know that pool chemicals can be reactive and can be a dangerous good?
Other products used outdoors such as pesticides and weed killers can be toxic or hazardous
to the environment.
Some items generally used while landscaping such as lawnmowers that contain gasoline
and lithium powered leaf blowers can also be dangerous goods.
Oh, and here is the family dog Bailey.
Products for Bailey such as flea, lice, and tick controls may be toxic and therefore are
dangerous goods.
Fireworks are entertaining but they are considered an explosive.
Let's talk about dangerous goods that are strictly prohibited from entering Amazon fulfillment
centers.
For example, spontaneously combustible products, toxic gases, products containing infectious
substances, and explosives.
Let's recap.
Items categorized and regulated as dangerous goods are commonly found in homes, many of
which can be sold in the Amazon marketplace.
Items used in this video are common examples and do not include every regulated dangerous
good.
Amazon's seller help in Seller Central and videos on Seller University are a great resource
for learning more including links to information provided by regulatory authorities.
Thank you for helping keep our communities and our customers safe.